

# Przemysław Boruta Machine Learning Expert

### **ABOUT ME**

Former product manager with 3 years of broad-based experience in developing web applications and processes related to corporate clients' credit needs and automating data. Now a machine learning expert with wide range of experience in both NLP and CV, but also with knowledge of MLOps tools.



ADDRESS Bukowinska 22





PHONE

+48 726 973 060



# **TECH:**

- **Deep Learning**: scikit-learn, Tensorflow - keras, flair, pytorch
- Computer Vision: Tesseract, pytesseract, TrOCR, YOLOv5, LayoutLM
- Natural Language Processing: transformers, FastText, Laser, spacy
- Workflows: Airflow, Celery
- **REST frameworks**: FastAPI, Flask
- **Data/-flow**: PostgreSQL, MsSQL, Oracle, Elastic, RabbitMQ, Kafka
- *MLOps*: Kubernetes, OCP, Docker, Jenkins, Vault

### **EXPERIENCE**

02.2023 - now

Machine Learning Expert • PKO Bank Polski • Warsaw, PL

2022 - 01.2023

Machine Learning Senior Specialist • PKO Bank Polski • Warsaw, PL

2020-2021

Sr. Product Development Specialist • ING Bank Śląski • Warsaw, PL

05.2019-06.2019

Credit Risk Modelling Specialist • ING Bank Śląski • Warsaw, PL

2018-2020

Product Development Specialist • ING Bank Śląski • Warsaw, PL

## Most notable projects:

- Document (scans) classification with data detection (e.g. sender's data, data of the person to whom the document relates; about 25 data types) w/ asynchronous processing
- Intent recognition, named entity recognition, fuzzy matching models for chatbots
- Anomaly detection in IT infrastructure
- Sensitive data detector (GDPR) in short notes in company's CRM software
- Topic modelling

# **EDUCATION**

2016-2021

SGH Warsaw School of Economics, Warsaw, PL

Quantitative Methods in Economics and Information Systems (PL)

Bachelor's: 2016-2019 Master's: 2019-2021

"I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realizing the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)".